- [Instructor] Web3.js
is the JavaScript Library
that we're going to use to
interact with our DApps.
This open source project is the standard
for how we are going to
interact from our client-side
applications to the Ethereum Network.
As of the recording of this course,
the current stable version is 0.20.
1.0 is currently in beta
however, I think its a
better implementation
and it's starting to become the standard
even though it's in beta right now.
So a lot of people are using it.
There are a few different
ways you can install it.
If you want to, you can
install it using Node or Yarn,
or Meteor if you're using such a thing.
They do have a CDN link
if you want to use that.
That makes it easy, so it's
then in a distributed network
so it will download it from the closest
one essentially, in the CDN.
I'm gonna go ahead and just grab
the distribution code directly from here.
So the first thing that I want to do is
I want to select 1.0 Branch
and then I can go into the dist directory
and in here I'm going to
grab the the minimized one.
You can see this is all one line
so all the white space has been removed
it's been compressed so that
it's a smallest size possible.
I'm going to go the the raw
and I'm just going go to Save Page As
and I'm going to save it into my
web directory which is in my desktop.
This is where I am essentially keeping
everything that I am
using for my client UI
and I am going to save web3min.js.
So now I've got the JavaScript file.
If you look you can see inside web3.js,
they have a number of different
packages that you can use.
The utils one is helpful.
There are some things
in here that you can do
in terms of setting the provider,
in terms of outputting
the version of web3.js,
whatever it is that you want to do.
Another important package is web3.eth.
This is what's going to allow us to
interact directly with the blockchain.
So I can access the Coinbase
of a particular block.
I can look at transactions.
I can go in and see different accounts
and what their balances are,
there's all kinds of stuff I can do.
This is how I can send Ether.
All the stuff is available in here.
So let's go ahead and
plug web3 into our DApp.
Here is our DApp interface.
Notice that I've opened up
my Java Console by going
to Developer, JavaScript
Console in Chrome.
I'm going to go into my code here
and the first thing I'm gonna do is
I'm going to add web3.min.js as a script
and I am going to create
another script block.
Then I am going to create
an instance of web3
called web3, and this
is going to say new Web3
and it's going to pass in an HTTP provider
Web3.providers.
9545 is the address of
the truffle test server.
So that's going to create an instance of
my web3 object that I can use.
So I am now going to use it,
to get the version, just to
output something to the log.
So let's go ahead and
go back in and refresh
and you can see it's saying
using web3 version 1.0.0-beta.34.
So that's the one I am using.
The one other thing I might want to do
is if I want to enable
interaction with MetaMask,
MetaMask will inject it's own web3.
So what I can do is I
can do a test to see.
And then on this test I can
then say web3 so if it exists,
I'm essentially going to
create an instance using
my local script but
accessing that provider.
And then here I can just type in
and copy this.
So that way if I do have MetaMask running
it would actually use it.
So if I were to run this
through MetaMask, through a web server,
so the web server served it up,
it would then access MetaMask's version
of web3 so to speak, it
would use the provider
that I had entered in MetaMask, up here.
And it would allow me to interact
using the accounts that were in here.
So as you can see here
web3 is fairly easy to implement
and it enables us to do a lot
in interacting with the
Ethereum blockchain.